<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book-review on rubot</title>
    <link>https://rubot99.github.io/tags/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book-review on rubot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 20:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rubot99.github.io/tags/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Soft Skills - The software developer&#39;s life manual</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/09/review-soft-skills-the-software-developers-life-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/09/review-soft-skills-the-software-developers-life-manual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;Soft Skills: The Software Developer&amp;rsquo;s Life Manual&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; is a book written by John Somnez, I first heard of John on the Dot Net Rocks podcast. After that I started to following his fitness podcast Get UP and Code. Nowadays I mainly follow him on his YouTube channel ‘Simple Programmer’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - The Phoenix Project</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/09/review-the-phoenix-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/09/review-the-phoenix-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘The Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win’&lt;/strong&gt; is a book about common situations you face working on software projects. The book teaches concepts and ideas through story form, it is very similar to books like the ‘One minute manager’ and ‘The richest man in Babylon’. I’ve read both these books and enjoyed how the simple truths and ideas are very cleverly conveyed through the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Art of Discarding</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-art-of-discarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-art-of-discarding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The art of discarding is about mainly changing our mind set so that we have a positive attitude towards discarding items that we don’t use. The book goes through attitudes and strategies to discard items by giving different scenarios and how to overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Refactoring - Improving the design of existing code - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-refactoring-improving-the-design-of-existing-code-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-refactoring-improving-the-design-of-existing-code-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-3&#34;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter is all about various code smells and how we can try to identify them.
The first code smell is duplicated code. Duplicated code means more places to make code changes and higher risks of bugs being added. The best way to fix this issue is to either extract the code into a new method or into a different class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Refactoring - Improving the design of existing code - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-refactoring-improving-the-design-of-existing-code-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-refactoring-improving-the-design-of-existing-code-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-2&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals-of-refactoring&#34;&gt;Goals of refactoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refactoring code makes a code base easier to understand and modify.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refactoring does not change observable the observable behaviour of the software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Refactoring - Improving the design of existing code - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-refactoring-improving-the-design-of-existing-code-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/08/review-refactoring-improving-the-design-of-existing-code-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m an avid listener of the CodingBlocks.Net podcasts and it’s been one of my go to podcasts for software development. I have especially enjoyed the podcasts where the presenters reviewed the Clean Code book by having a podcast per chapter where they discussed their individual thoughts. So I thought I would follow their idea and write blogs posts reviewing Martin Fowler’s book on Refactoring. This year I wanted to read a few software development books and write a few posts, so what better way to merge my two goals reading the book and writing posts for the sections/chapters 😉&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Test Driven Development by Example</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/04/review-test-driven-development-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/04/review-test-driven-development-by-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another of my new year resolutions is to read three computer science related books. So, the first book I choose was Kent Beck’s book on TDD. I would say this book is the quintessential book on test driven development. I have owned this book for quite a few years but have never gotten around to reading it. So finally, I have taken plunge and have completed reading the book 😊.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>