<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rubot</title>
    <link>https://rubot99.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on rubot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rubot99.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with Blogging Platforms</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/03/experiments-with-blogging-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/03/experiments-with-blogging-platforms/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/wordpressBlog.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Rubot Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/hugo.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hugo Site Generator&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World Reboot</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/03/hello-world-reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2017/03/hello-world-reboot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been about 4 years since I last blogged, stuff has got in the way and I have just not been bothered. Anyway this year I want to start blogging again – a hello world reboot ;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this year one my resolutions has been to write twelve blog post by December 2017. Hopefully by the end of the year I would have achieved this goal. I’m going to try and blog on technology, development and my experience on keto.
To kick start my blogging goal I decided to use a new blogging platform. I’ve got my new blog all set up now. So I guess rubot is locked and loaded :)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/killerrobot.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Killer Robot&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ddd North 2012</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/10/ddd-north-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/10/ddd-north-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I attended the DDD North 2 event at Bradford Business School. It was another excellent event. As usual it was well organised and with an excellent line up of talks. This was my third DDD event so far and I thoroughly enjoyed it. I have to admit I wasn’t sure if I wanted to go this year since I didn’t think I would be interested in many of the talk, but I’m glad I did go since some of the talks that I thought I wouldn’t be interested were really useful and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/bradfordBusinessSchool.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Bradford Business School&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It was an early start on Saturday with a few minor car troubles, which was sorted out quite quickly. I got to the event a little before registration and the venue was very nice. Once there I grabbed a coffee and scouted out the rooms where the talks were being held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sessions I finally decided on where:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;windows-8-apps-mike-taulty&#34;&gt;‘Windows 8 Apps’ – Mike Taulty&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a very good session introducing both Windows 8 and Windows 8 app development. I really liked the touch screen Mike was using for his demos. It got me really interested in Windows 8 and WinRT app development. All I need now is to update my 5 year old PC and install Windows 8 &amp;amp; VS 2012 on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;async-c-5-0-patterns-for-real-world-use-liam-westley&#34;&gt;‘Async C# 5.0 – Patterns for real world use’ – Liam Westley&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have attended other talks by Liam and have always found his talks to be very interesting and the subject matter always useful. This was one of the talks I wasn’t really interested in, but was pleasantly surprised that it was one of the best talks I attended during the event. It was very interesting and as Liam was going through his demos I could see places in my own projects where I could use the Async patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;selenium-a-ui-testing-paradigm-nathan-gloyn&#34;&gt;‘Selenium a UI testing paradigm’ – Nathan Gloyn&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have attended two other talks by Nathan, SOLID principle and Kanban which were both excellent talks. Since I have heard about Selenium, but never really investigated it. I thought this might be a good introduction. The talk was very good, Nathan explained how to use the Selenium IDE and WebDriver for creating automated regression tests.

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/seleniumTalk.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Selenium Talk - Nathan Gloyn&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;web-sockets-and-signalr-building-the-real-time-interactive-web-chris-alcock&#34;&gt;‘Web Sockets and SignalR – Building the Real Time Interactive Web’ – Chris Alcock&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting talk and a good introduction to the topic. I haven’t really looked a lot into web sockets which could be due to my limited javascript knowledge, however I think its something I want to investigate further. The SignalR project actually looks really good and I think I might be able to use it in a couple applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;c-powershell-happy-couple-jimmy-skowronski&#34;&gt;‘C# + PowerShell = happy couple’ – Jimmy Skowronski&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to investigate and learn PowerShell , so when I saw this talk on the list I decided it would a good introduction to the subject area. Jimmy did a great job with the talk and I need to spend some time investigating PowerShell and creating power shell command in c#.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a Grok talk on OutSystems which looked really interesting and would be very useful in rapidly building/prototyping business application. I think it would be really useful in my current company since we sometime need to quickly build applications with a limited shelf life. These ‘limited shelf life’ applications tend be used for 3 -6 months and after that won’t be required. Also these application need to be built very quickly; often we may have a couple of days to deploy it. I’m going to have a look at OutSystems and LightSwitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was an excellent event and I took away a lot from the session. I am definitely going to use the Async patterns within my applications in the future and am going to look more into PowerShell and WinRT applications.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/dddNorth2012Event.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;DDD North 2012 Event Poster&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gate Sql In The City London</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/07/red-gate-sql-in-the-city-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/07/red-gate-sql-in-the-city-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I attended the Red Gate ‘SQL in the City’ event in London. It was one of the best free event that I have been to. The event was very well organised and had a great line up of sessions. There were three tracks of sessions DBA, Red Gate and Developer and I would have liked to attend all of them, but had to choose the ones I really wanted to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fortunately for me the great folks at Red Gate recorded all the sessions and announced that they would be made available for all the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started off with a cup of coffee in one of the best mugs ever!!! It was a mug with the top SQL Prompt snippets and I have to admit I didn’t know some of them. I am happy to report that those snippets are now being used extensively :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was kicked off by the welcome session from Simon Galbraith (Joint CEO of Red Gate). He discussed past Red Gate products and how getting customer feedback early in the development process had a significant impact on the commercial success of the products. I guess you could sum what he said to ‘Release soon, Release Often’ equals greater chance for commercial success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stared off with ‘Top Tips for Writing Better – T-SQL stored procedures’. This session was run by Grant Fritchey (ScaryDBA.com). I was quite surprised at how making a few changes to your query could improve it’s performance. It was a really good session for anyone who writes a bit of T-SQL, especially if you are writing queries against a legacy database that wasn’t designed well :(.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then attended the ‘Prepare for When disaster Strikes’, which was run by Steve Jones, Editor in Chief at SQLServerCentral.com. The session was targeted at DBAs, but as a developer the main thing I got was the importance of increasing your alert time since this gives you more time to react to a problem. I do see the benefit of this since I use Elmah in my web applications and getting a heads up before a user calls me has been extremely useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch I attended ‘Deployment Horrors and How to avoid them’ by Dave Ballantyne and followed that with ‘Case Study – How we learned to stop worrying and love Continuous Integration’ by Dave Green and Annette Allen from First Databank. For the final session I thought I would try a wild card session and went to the ‘SQL Azure from Plan, to Backup, to Cloud – Red Gate Cloud-Ready Services’. This session was run by Tobiasz Koprowski and Richard Mitchell. I was really surprised how much I liked the session. It was well presented and Tobiasz and Richard did a really great job. I had the misconception of thinking that Azure was SQL server in the cloud, unfortunately there are limitation to having SQL server in the cloud and these limitation aren’t only technical and can be geographic laws. Using Azure depends on the type of application your building and the data you will be storing, some applications are better suited for Azure than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a great event and I really enjoyed it and will definitely be looking out for the next ‘SQL in the City’ event.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sqlPromptMug.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;SQL Prompt coffee mug&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handled Unhandled Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/07/handled-unhandled-exceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/07/handled-unhandled-exceptions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Handled Unhandled Exception’ sounds like an oxy-moron, but let me explain what I mean.
I’m sure most developers have seen the code below at some point in their careers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
try
{
//code that does something
}
catch(Exception exc)
{}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think the catch section is missing some code your absolutely correct. Unfortunately I have seen this type of code quite a few times. This type of error handling is what I like to call a handled unhandled exception, the major problem here is that any unhandled exception is caught but nothing is ever done with it. It’s a nightmare to debug this kind of code because you never know whether the code returns no results or there was an exception thrown. In a real world application this code would be called by other functions which might also have the same style of exceptional handling and this turns out to be extremely difficult to debug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I would prefer that the developer wouldn’t wrap the code with a try and catch or atleast re-throw the exception.
In my opinion if you are going to handle an exception, handle them properly don’t just pseudo handle them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Intuitive User Interface Design Actually Subjective</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/05/is-intuitive-user-interface-design-actually-subjective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/05/is-intuitive-user-interface-design-actually-subjective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Microsoft Essentials as my antivirus program ever since it was released. I really like the clean and simple user interface and the small memory footprint. I also recommend it to everyone. However recently I noticed that I hadn’t run a system scan in a while and the Microsoft Essential icon had turned yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I opened Microsoft Essentials, the main window had a large yellow ‘Scan Now’ button. Since I hadn’t run a system scan for a while, I thought I should run a full scan instead of a quick scan. So I selected full scan from the scan options and then clicked the yellow ‘Scan Now’ button. What I expected to happen now was that Microsoft Essentials would start a full system scan, however what happened was a quick scan was started. This surprised me and at first I assumed that I had made a mistake. So after investigating this for a few weeks I realised that when you click the yellow ‘Scan Now’ button it always starts a quick scan regardless of what scan option was selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I thought this wasn’t intuitive, but after thinking about it more I started to wonder, if actually intuitiveness was subjective. Would another user actually expect that the application would run a quick scan when they clicked on the yellow ‘Scan Now’ button regardless of the scan option selected? Is there enough of a distinction between the regular scan now section and high priority yellow ‘Scan Now’ button to explain the difference of scan types that will be executed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was designing this process what I would do is check the scan type selected and run that particular scan. I agree that when a system scan hasn’t been run for a long time you would want to alert the user (large yellow button) and you would want the user to run a complete system scan. Running a quick system scan makes sense since it would take less time to complete and on a psychological level there is a higher probability that the scan would complete before the user decided to cancel it. I think this could be achieved by the fact that the quick scan is selected by default in the scan options section and if the user has made the decision to perform a full scan they expect it will take longer than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be quite interested in what anyone else thinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are screenshots of my process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Microsoft Essentials when the icon has turned yellow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sc12.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main window opens with the large yellow ‘Scan Now’ button visible and the quick scan option is selected by default. I then select the full scan option and click the yellow ‘Scan Now’ button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sc2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sc3.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You notice that a quick scan has been started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sc4.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After cancelling the scan I made sure the full scan option was selected and then clicked on the regular scan now button. This time a full scan is started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sc5.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/sc6.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Fuelled Business Event</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/03/web-fuelled-business-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2012/03/web-fuelled-business-event/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the Web Fuelled Business event at Castle Gate, Newcastle upon Tyne. This event was organised by the School for Startups. The speakers were Doug Richard and James Dening (click here for information on the speakers). In my opinion the event was very well organised and I did take away quite a bit from the sessions. The Castle Gate venue was a wonderful venue and the venue staffs were excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire event was held in the Turbine Hall. I got to the venue quite early so I did get to sit up front and got some pictures of Doug and James during their sessions. I enjoyed all the session and can’t really pick out a particular session that I really liked best.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/dougrichard.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doug Richard&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One of the things James discussed in his session on market places was scaling your business using Amazon’s delivery system. This was something that was totally new to me. James explained that Amazon will store and ship your products that have been sold through their Marketplace. He also discussed how he uses the Amazon delivery service for products bought from his Amazon Marketplace. I couldn’t believe what an amazing service Amazon provides for its sellers.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/jamesdening.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;James Dening&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There were certain things that were said that really caught my attention, they were
1. An entrepreneur has to stop being an inventor and move to put things around that idea to build a business – As a software developer I can really relate to this. I often find myself excited about the technology or architecture of a system and forget about the selling of that product or service.
2. Low prices and large selection are essential for e-commerce websites.
3. Sacrifice short term profits for long term customer retention. – I guess ‘The Customer is still King’
4. Being on Page 2 of a Google search result is like being in Internet Siberia – This really brings home the point how much search engines impact our browsing of the internet.
5. The war of the click is greater than the war of price. – Reduce the barriers to your site. Too many clicks are just too much effort.
6. Video testimonials on your website have a great impact on your customer’s selection process and are anxiety reducers. Your landing page should have anxiety reducers for your site visitors to help increase their trust in your site.
7. Social media is the Amplification of word of mouth.
8. Don’t create obstacles to outcomes. – This really hit home for me and I started to think about how I have created obstacles in other areas to prevent successful outcomes.
Overall it was an excellent event and I would definitely recommend it to anyone else. Also I would definitely attend the next Web Fuelled event in Newcastle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Devexpress Gridview Control</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/using-devexpress-gridview-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/using-devexpress-gridview-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another post in my series of DevExpress controls that I use and like. In this post I will be looking at the ASPxGridView control. This control is one of my most used and favourite DevExpress controls. The functionality that you get straight out of the box is impressive to say the least. I’m able to add functionality that is extremely useful to the users with very little effort or code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The features that I like in the control are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data sorting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data grouping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colum re-arrangement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The features that I have listed are features that come straight out the box. I tend to normally bind the GridView to a list of business objects and either enable or disable the features through the control markup. I find these features really useful since I don’t need to write extra code on the application side nor do I have any additional views or stored procedures
on the database side. I should mention that depending on what you do with data editing you make need to handle row events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The features that I like the best is the data grouping functionality and the reason for this is that it allows users to group on any column they need to. The first screen shot shows the default gridview without any grouping. The second screen shot shows what happens when the user groups on one of the columns and the third screen shot shows what happens when the grouping is on two different columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/default3.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Devexpress Gridview Control&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/groupontwocolumns1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Data Grouping example 1&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/groupononecolumn2.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Data Grouping example 2&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using DevExpress ASP.Net Spin Editor Control</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/using-devexpress-asp.net-spin-editor-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/using-devexpress-asp.net-spin-editor-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DevExpress ASP.Net spin editor control is one of those simple but extremely useful controls. I tend to use this control a lot in my projects. It basically is a text input field which only allows the user to enter numeric data.
I know on the face of it does not seem revolutionary, but a few things I like about the control are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small and large increment buttons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control features can be setup through markup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control value can be retrieved as either a string or int/decimal value (this saves writing code that casts to a string or int/decimal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the markup for the spin edit control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dx:ASPxSpinEdit ID=&amp;quot;dxspinAmount&amp;quot; runat=&amp;quot;server&amp;quot; Height=&amp;quot;21px&amp;quot; Number=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; NumberType=&amp;quot;Integer&amp;quot; Increment=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot; AllowNull=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; Enabled=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; &amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;SpinButtons Position=&amp;quot;Left&amp;quot; ShowLargeIncrementButtons=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/SpinButtons&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dx:ASPxSpinEdit&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://rubot99.github.io/images/spinedit.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;ASP.Net Spin Editor Control&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robot Band On Engadget</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/robot-band-on-engadget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/robot-band-on-engadget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of weeks ago I came across this post on the engadget website about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/2011/07/18/robot-band-covers-marilyn-manson-renders-sullen-teenagers-obsol/&#34;&gt;robotic band called ‘End of Life’&lt;/a&gt;.
The video shows the band covering ‘The Beautiful People’ by Marilyn Manson. I thought it was extremely cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9QMtDyvAzVw
&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.youtube.com/vi/9QMtDyvAzVw/0.jpg&#34; 
alt=&#34;IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; border=&#34;10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Like About Instagram Hipstamatic</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/07/things-i-like-about-instagram-hipstamatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/07/things-i-like-about-instagram-hipstamatic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of months I have been getting into iPhone photography or as it is more popularly known as iPhoneography.
I started out by using Instagram and have now graduated to using both Instagram and Hipstamatic.
At first glance I thought these apps were similar and favoured Instagram because of its ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However on further examination of Hipstamatic I realised that these apps are for different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-i-like-about-instagram&#34;&gt;Things I like about Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a picture to your Instagram feed is quick and easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to process pictures taken previously or with another camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-i-like-about-hipstamatic&#34;&gt;Things I like about Hipstamatic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large number of lens, film and flash options which provide a variety of effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional lens, film and flash packs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to get hard copy prints of your pictures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After using both apps for sometime I have realised both apps are a must for my iphone photography kit. I like to take quick pictures with the iPhone camera app and then later review and process them with Instagram. When I have time to try different compositions, I like to use Hipstamatic as it gives me more options. Both these apps are great and I would recommend them to anyone starting out with iPhone photography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Devexpress Winforms Treelist Control</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/07/using-devexpress-winforms-treelist-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/07/using-devexpress-winforms-treelist-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using the DevExpress WinForms &amp;amp; ASP.Net controls at work. I have been surprised by the many useful features that you get straight out of the box. I mostly work with the ASP.Net controls, but recently I have been using the DevExpress TreeList WinForm controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to and when the user clicks the third level it displays relevant information to the user.
One of the things that I found really interesting was that your business object can implement the IVirtualTreeListData interface, this will then allow you to create the hierarchical structure for your business objects and then you will be able to directly bind a list of these objects to the tree list. For my current project I did not want to implement this interface directly in my entities. I thought it would be better to define a class that only catered to the concerns related to the tree list and did not expose all the details of the entity. Below is the TreeNode class that implements the IVirtualTreeListData.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public class TreeNode : TreeList.IVirtualTreeListData
{
 protected TreeNode parentNode;
 protected List childrenNodes = new List();
 protected string _name;
 protected int _id;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
 
 public TreeNode (TreeNode parent, string name, int id)
 {
  this.parentNode = parent;
 
  _name = name;
  _id = id;
 
  if(this.parentNode != null)
  this.parentNode.childrenNodes.Add(this);
 } 
 
 public void VirtualTreeGetCellValue(VirtualTreeGetCellValueInfo info)
 {
  if (info.Column.AbsoluteIndex == 0)
   info.CellData = _name;
  else
   info.CellData = _id;
 }
 
 public void VirtualTreeGetChildNodes(VirtualTreeGetChildNodesInfo info)
 {
  info.Children = childrenNodes;
 }
 
 public void VirtualTreeSetCellValue(VirtualTreeSetCellValueInfo info)
 {
  if (info.Column.AbsoluteIndex == 0)
   _name = info.NewCellData.ToString();
  else
   _id = (int)info.NewCellData;
 }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the method that populates the TreeNodes with data from your entities and binds to the treelist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private void SetupControls()
{
 //This sections sets up the tree list columns. I only display the fist column to the user. The second is used to  retrieve the additional information for the user.
 TreeListColumn col1 = new TreeListColumn();
 col1.Caption = &amp;quot;Name&amp;quot;;
 col1.VisibleIndex = 0;
 TreeListColumn col2 = new TreeListColumn();
 col2.Caption = &amp;quot;Id&amp;quot;;
 col2.VisibleIndex = 1;
 col2.Visible = false;
 treeList1.Columns.AddRange(new TreeListColumn[] { col1, col2 });
 //Here we create the root node for the treelist
 TreeNode datasource = new TreeNode(null, null, 0);
 //Iterate through the list of your entities to create the level 1, level 2 and level 3 nodes for
 tree list.
 foreach (TreeBusinessObject treenode in GetNodeObjects())
 {
  TreeNode node = new TreeNode(datasource, treenode.Node, 0);
  TreeNode subnode = new TreeNode(node, treenode.SubNode, 0);&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
 
  foreach (var item in treenode.GetChildSubNodes())
  {
   TreeNode childnode = new TreeNode(subnode, item, treenode.Id);
  }
 }
 //Bind to the tree list
 treeList1.DataSource = datasource;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also adding the code for my business object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public class TreeBusinessObject
{
 public int Id { get; set; }
 public string Node { get; set; }
 public string SubNode { get; set; }&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
 
 private List childSubNode;
 
 public TreeBusinessObject()
 {
  childSubNode = new List();
 }
 
 public TreeBusinessObject(int id)
 {
  Id = id;
  Node = String.Format(&amp;quot;Node {0}&amp;quot;, id.ToString());
  SubNode = String.Format(&amp;quot;Sub Node {0}&amp;quot;, id.ToString());
 
  childSubNode = new List();
  AddChildNode(String.Format(&amp;quot;Child A1_{0}&amp;quot;, id.ToString()));
  AddChildNode(String.Format(&amp;quot;Child A2_{0}&amp;quot;, id.ToString()));
  AddChildNode(String.Format(&amp;quot;Child A3_{0}&amp;quot;, id.ToString()));
 }
 
 public void AddChildNode(string childnode)
 {
  childSubNode.Add(childnode);
 }
 
 public List GetChildSubNodes()
 {
  return childSubNode;
 }
 
 public void RemoveChildNode(string childnode)
 {
  childSubNode.Remove(childnode);
 }
 
 public void ClearAllChildNodes()
 {
  childSubNode.Clear();
 }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked that your business object can implement an interface and then directly bind a list of business objects to the tree list. Initially when I was working with the control I did not realise that there was a difference between selected nodes and focused nodes, but after using the control the difference is clear. The only thing I couldn’t figure out was setting the state of the tree list i.e. whether is was expanded or collapsed.
For for more information about binding a treelist to your business objects refer to the DevExpress documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Developer, Developer Scotland 2011</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/05/developer-developer-developer-scotland-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/05/developer-developer-developer-scotland-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the Developer, Developer, Developer event in Glasgow. It was the first time I have been to a DDD event and I have to say I thoroughly enjoyed it. The event was well organised and the content in the sessions were excellent. The event thoroughly exceeded my expectations. There were so many interesting sessions that if I had the chance I would have attended them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended the following sessions at DDD:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CQRS and Friends: Possibly distributed systems, intentionally  – Andrea Magnorsky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an introductory session on CQRS/ES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caliburn.Micro: Painless MVVM apps for Silverlight and WPF – Barry Carr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session was a good introduction to using Caliburn Micro with Silverlight. The step by step code demo on using Caliburn Micro was really useful and good. Caliburn Micro seems like a really cool MVVM framework and I am planning try it out on a small project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unit Testing, Test Driven Development and the Walking Skeleton – Seb Rose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A detailed talk explaining TDD and the pros and pit falls you might face when using TDD in your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your code S.O.L.I.D? – Nathan Gloyn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially was expecting this talk to be a detailed description about SOLID principles, but was pleasantly surprised to see that Nathan had code examples too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functional Alchemy: Tricks to keep your C# DRY* – Mark Rendle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was another excellent session with a great code demo. One of the things Mark discussed was a try-catch functional strategy which I think I’m going to start using in my code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great developer event and I am tempted to go to the DDD South West event next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Mercurial Dev Shop</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/04/setting-up-mercurial-dev-shop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/04/setting-up-mercurial-dev-shop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time I have wanted to use a distributed source control management tool at work. I have looked at both Mercurial and Git and decided that I would like try Mercurial. So recently I have had the opportunity to use Mercurial on a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used Visual Source Safe briefly and have mostly used Subversion with TortoiseSVN. So I found it quite easy to switch to TortoiseHg. I am still getting to grips with Mercurial, but I have really enjoyed using it and think I will permanently move to using Mercurial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I wanted to setup a stable repository for the project so that I could push my changes to a Mercurial server and in the future setup cruise control to pull the changes from a central location. Also it would allow my manager to view the changes without having TortosieHg installed on his machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are a Microsoft dev shop, I decided it would be easier to setup Mercurial on IIS. I found quite a few posts on setting up Mercurial on IIS 7, but had quite a difficult time getting it to work. I have also found differences in the setup process for Windows Server 2008 R2 (64 bit) and Windows Server 2008 (32 bit). So in this post I am going to list the blog articles that helped me to setup a Mercurial server successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off by experimenting on a Windows Server 2008 (32 bit) VM (Virtual Machine). After many attempts I finally found a combination of two blogs post that helped me get Mercurial running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jake Murzy’s Blog – Installing and Setting Up Mercurial on Windows/IIS7 running Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Hawley – Setting up Mercurial server in IIS7 using a ISAPI module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: I didn’t have a problem installing isapi-wsgi on the virtual machine since the virtual machine had the MSVCR71.dll file in the System32 folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VM Details: 32-bit Microsoft Windows Server 2008, 1GB RAM and 16GB HDD running on VMWare server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Virtual Machine also had the following software products installed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Firefox/Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 zip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notepad++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VM Ware tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IIS 7 with IIS 6 Management Compatibility and Application development services installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After following the instructions from the two posts I got the Mercurial web interface working. However when I came to install it on a server running Windows 2008 R2 (64 bit), I couldn’t seem to get it to work. So after googling a bit I found the following post which helped me get Mercurial setup on my server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stacking Code – &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackingcode.com/blog/2011/02/24/running-a-mercurial-server-on-iis-7-5-windows-server-2008-r2&#34;&gt;Running a Mercurial Server on IIS 7.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for a Personal Backup Strategy – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/05/the-quest-for-a-personal-backup-strategy--part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 20:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/05/the-quest-for-a-personal-backup-strategy--part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my final post on my personal backup strategy. In this post I am going to state which service I decided to go with.
At the end of my last post I couldn’t decide between Backblaze and Mozy since I liked both backup services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They both had excellent products and I couldn’t really fault them in any area. So it finally came down to personal preference and I decided to go with Backblaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my free trial again and had about 13 GB backed up with the trial period. I then purchased the yearly subcription ($50). I first started to backup all important folders and used the exclusion list to avoid backing up certain folders. After that I backed up the rest of my data, I now have a total of 20 GB backed up on Backblaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a little information on how I tested the services. I built two virtual machines and setup the two services on each machine. I would drop different file types and sizes to see how long the backup would take. Also I checked how long it took for me to be able to access the data from the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using Backblaze for over a month and am very happy with the service they provide. I haven’t had any issues with browsing the internet while a backup was in progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>