<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo tranquilpeak theme</title>
    <link>https://rubot99.github.io/categories/photography/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hugo tranquilpeak theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://rubot99.github.io/categories/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Like About Instagram Hipstamatic</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/07/things-i-like-about-instagram-hipstamatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/07/things-i-like-about-instagram-hipstamatic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of months I have been getting into iPhone photography or as it is more popularly known as iPhoneography.
I started out by using Instagram and have now graduated to using both Instagram and Hipstamatic.
At first glance I thought these apps were similar and favoured Instagram because of its ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However on further examination of Hipstamatic I realised that these apps are for different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-i-like-about-instagram&#34;&gt;Things I like about Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a picture to your Instagram feed is quick and easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to process pictures taken previously or with another camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-i-like-about-hipstamatic&#34;&gt;Things I like about Hipstamatic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large number of lens, film and flash options which provide a variety of effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional lens, film and flash packs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to get hard copy prints of your pictures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After using both apps for sometime I have realised both apps are a must for my iphone photography kit. I like to take quick pictures with the iPhone camera app and then later review and process them with Instagram. When I have time to try different compositions, I like to use Hipstamatic as it gives me more options. Both these apps are great and I would recommend them to anyone starting out with iPhone photography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>