<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo tranquilpeak theme</title>
    <link>https://rubot99.github.io/tags/tech/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hugo tranquilpeak theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://rubot99.github.io/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Robot Band On Engadget</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/robot-band-on-engadget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2011/08/robot-band-on-engadget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of weeks ago I came across this post on the engadget website about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/2011/07/18/robot-band-covers-marilyn-manson-renders-sullen-teenagers-obsol/&#34;&gt;robotic band called ‘End of Life’&lt;/a&gt;.
The video shows the band covering ‘The Beautiful People’ by Marilyn Manson. I thought it was extremely cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9QMtDyvAzVw
&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.youtube.com/vi/9QMtDyvAzVw/0.jpg&#34; 
alt=&#34;IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; border=&#34;10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for a Personal Backup Strategy – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/05/the-quest-for-a-personal-backup-strategy--part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 20:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/05/the-quest-for-a-personal-backup-strategy--part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my final post on my personal backup strategy. In this post I am going to state which service I decided to go with.
At the end of my last post I couldn’t decide between Backblaze and Mozy since I liked both backup services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They both had excellent products and I couldn’t really fault them in any area. So it finally came down to personal preference and I decided to go with Backblaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my free trial again and had about 13 GB backed up with the trial period. I then purchased the yearly subcription ($50). I first started to backup all important folders and used the exclusion list to avoid backing up certain folders. After that I backed up the rest of my data, I now have a total of 20 GB backed up on Backblaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a little information on how I tested the services. I built two virtual machines and setup the two services on each machine. I would drop different file types and sizes to see how long the backup would take. Also I checked how long it took for me to be able to access the data from the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using Backblaze for over a month and am very happy with the service they provide. I haven’t had any issues with browsing the internet while a backup was in progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quest Personal Backup Strategy - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/03/quest-personal-backup-strategy---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/03/quest-personal-backup-strategy---part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This second post is to clarify questions I had about some of the cloud based backup solutions. I haven’t tried out Jungle Disk, since the pay as you use storage costs would be too expensive for me. Also with Jungle Disk you would need to pay for the product and the storage costs. This would be expensive for me and so haven’t investigated the service further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for me personally it has come down to either Mozy or Backblaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mozy&#34;&gt;Mozy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can customise the backup sets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozy account can be used to backup more than one computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you supply a personal encryption key, the contents of your files are encrypted, but you can still view the file names from the web interface. I like using my own encryption key, but having to download a decryption utility means that I can’t easily get my data on another machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;backblaze&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like that if you supply your personal encryption key you don’t have to use a decryption tool to retrieve your data. This makes it easy to get your data from another machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used both products and can’t really make up mind on which one I like better. Both products have their salient features. I’ll update this post when I finally decide which product I want to go with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mozy.com/home&#34;&gt;http://mozy.com/home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jungledisk.com/personal/&#34;&gt;http://www.jungledisk.com/personal/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.backblaze.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.backblaze.com/2008/11/12/how-to-make-strong-encryption-easy-to-use/&#34;&gt;http://blog.backblaze.com/2008/11/12/how-to-make-strong-encryption-easy-to-use/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carbonite.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.carbonite.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quest Personal Backup Strategy - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/03/quest-personal-backup-strategy---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rubot99.github.io/2010/03/quest-personal-backup-strategy---part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start by saying that I am continuously trying to improve my backup strategy. From my experience I believe that a backup strategy will evolve as your needs change and a one size fits all doesn’t really work. So for this reason I am always asking people how they backup their important data and reading blog posts on people’s backup strategies. All this helps me to refine my backup strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I plan to describe how my backup strategy has evolved over the years. Now I want to use one of the cloud based storage services to backup my data and will try to give you reasons why I am going choose one of these services over the others. The services I plan to look at are Jungle Disk (Amazon S3), Dropbox, Mozy, Backblaze and Carbonite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at university, I used to backup my data to floppy disks &amp;amp; CD-R and then to flash drives. After finishing university I found I didn’t have a lot to backup and could get away with backing up a few times a year to DVD-R. This all changed after Apple introduced their iTunes store. I started to buy music from them and was backing up to DVD-R. Now I have started to buy music from the iTunes store and Amazon. This makes it difficult to backup the music and basically I have to put more effort to backup the data. Before I didn’t have a lot of documents and pictures to backup and so a limited backup was fine, but over the years the number of my documents and pictures have increased dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I need to backup more regularly and I have been using external hard drives and DVD-R. One problem with this method is I can’t automate the backup since I use more than one external hard drive. Also I don’t have an offsite backup and if the external hard drive fails I’ll lose my data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-based-backup-solutions&#34;&gt;Cloud based Backup Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been interested in cloud based storage. I have looked at reviews of the different services and I couldn’t really make up my mind. Since most of these services have a trial offer, I decided to try them out myself and decide which one would suit me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dropbox&#34;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using the free Dropbox account for some time now and I really like the service. I like the simplicity of the service. I like the simplicity of dropping files into the dropbox folder and your data is backed up.  For the amount of data I need to backup, the dropbox paid accounts are too expensive for me. I will continue to use the free account since I find it a quick and easy way of sharing files between my desktop and laptop computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;carbonite&#34;&gt;Carbonite&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I could find nothing wrong with Carbonite.  The only feature it seemed to lack was the ability to browse your files online. I couldn’t find a way of viewing the backed up files from another machine without installing the Carbonite software.  Since the Mozy and Backblaze offers this feature, it would have been nice for Carbonite to provide it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;backblaze&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very interested in Backblaze after seeing the video and blog post about the storage pods they have designed. I think their service is really good and will suit most people. It takes away the hassle of deciding what needs to be backed up and I can see this being really useful. However for me I want a little more control. The initial backup took quite some time. I tried to find a way to customize what is being backed up, but didn’t have much luck. I only found a way of adding files or folders to a ignore list. It would have been nice to tell the software what I wanted to add to the backup set instead of adding what I didn’t want backed up. This is a drawback for me, but I think I may need to investigate it further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mozy&#34;&gt;Mozy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozy seems to meet all my requirements; you can customize the backup set and change the schedules of your backup. You have a nice web interface to access your files. I think for me Mozy is the best solution for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far Mozy seems to be the backup solutions that would be ideal for me. I will be using my Dropbox account to share files between my laptop and desktop computers. I think I am going to give Backblaze another look and check if I can back up what I want by using the ignore list. I have to admit I think their storage pods are really cool. I am also going to try to look at Amazon S3, but the pay for what you use model may be too expensive for me.  I will try out the Jungle Disk service and investigate Backblaze further in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mozy.com/home&#34;&gt;http://mozy.com/home&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jungledisk.com/personal/&#34;&gt;http://www.jungledisk.com/personal/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.backblaze.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.backblaze.com/2008/11/12/how-to-make-strong-encryption-easy-to-use/&#34;&gt;http://blog.backblaze.com/2008/11/12/how-to-make-strong-encryption-easy-to-use/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carbonite.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.carbonite.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>